Good evening!
I bought quite a bit of groceries today
It's been raining a lot these days and the humidity is very high
Because of this, washing my hands after returning home feels extra good
The presence of daffodils at the grocery store is a clear indication that Spring is just around the corner
Flowers are one of those small things that can make me happy for days
Poppies are my favorite flowers ~ they bloom like living masterpieces, each one a true work of art
I like to quickly "prepare" my groceries once I get home
Cutting the butter into small pieces will make it so much more convenient to use when you need it
However, I don't use separators between pieces (I am a "little" frugal in that regard haha (⸝⸝ᵕᴗᵕ⸝⸝))
As long as you leave a bit of space between the pieces, they won't stick together even if they fall
For vegetables, I like to clean them and then let them dry before storing them in the fridge
Dirt trapped in the vegetables can carry bacteria which may lead to contamination
Berries are Koko's favourite fruit, so I usually buy a lot and wash them all at once
I give them a quick rinse and then soak them in baking soda water for 15 minutes
Baking soda helps to remove dirt, pesticides, and other residues effectively
You can leave the berries to air dry, but it usually takes really long, so I like to use a salad spinner
I promise it's not just because the salad spinner would otherwise sit unused... 𓏗-𓏗
For proteins, I like to remove them from their packaging as soon as I get home
It's a habit my mother-in-law taught me long ago, and it really stuck with me
She mentioned that this helps reduce the chances of plastic leaching into the food, and I've followed her advice ever since
Every Friday afternoon, 🐢 takes 🐨 out to play, so I have some time for myself before dinner
I've been loving rooibos and rose tea lately
I think they complement each other perfectly ~
The aroma is very delicate, sweet, and soothing ~
Pouring it into the biggest mug I have 😅
The flavour is so rich and mellow at the same time, and so comforting ~
I brewed extra tea to enjoy later
We've been eating out a lot lately with relatives visiting, so I've really been craving 'home food'
I reckon 'home food' is different for everyone, but for me, it’s either pasta or rice with stir-fried dishes
I guess it’s a blend of my Chinese heritage and being born and raised in Italy
What's your version of 'home food'?
Tonight, I'm going to be making Chinese style food ~
Boiling the pork with a bit of ginger for 5 minutes helps to remove any unpleasant odors
For the sauce, I'm using 1/2 tbsp tamari, 1 tbsp oyster sauce, and 1/2 tbsp sugar
Fry the ginger in a bit of oil until fragrant
Then add in your protein of choice and fry until golden brown
Finally, add the vegetables and sauce
Many combinations of proteins and vegetables can work with this recipe
(Can you tell Koko came home? 😆)
The second dish (Koko's favourite dish) is a child's favourite
I have so many memories of eating steamed eggs mixed with rice when I was a kid
Typically, you'd sift the eggs like I'm doing here to achieve the smoothest texture
However, since we're at home (and eggs are expensive), I just use them as they are
I like to steam the mixture for 5 minutes before adding my toppings and steaming for 6 more minutes
(I got distracted and steamed them for 8 minutes before adding the toppings, but it was fine)
Lastly, I'll boil some romaine lettuce
In reality, I've been multitasking all the dishes, but I think it's easier to watch this way? 😆
The romaine lettuce is ready to be served after about 30 seconds
I'm going to make a quick sauce with a bit of garlic, soy sauce, and sugar
Serving dinner with some mixed purple rice ~
🐢&🐨:"Thanks Mamma"
🐨:"Steamed egg, steamed egg 🎶"
It's so delicious ~ Rice killers for sure
After dinner, it's time to get Koko ready for bed
Lately, we've been showering together for efficiency
It also makes story time cosier and more enjoyable for the both of us since we can cuddle together ~
🐻:"Why is he happy?" 🐨:"Because he ate so much food!" 😆
🐨:"He ate lots of rice! and steamed eggs!"
We used to read the same books to her when she was a baby, but in a very different manner
These days, we talk about why the characters may be feeling a certain way
🐨:"We can help her put on a bandaid and she'll feel happy!"
After reading some stories, we usually cuddle for a few more minutes before she sleeps in her own bed
After hearing much about the benefits of red light, I recently bought a red light mask 👍
I'm usually very good at taking it slow, but there are 2 times where I can't!
When brushing my teeth and doing a mask 😆 I feel like I have to keep myself busy
I purchased a brush cleaner from Amazon and I thought I'd use this time to clean my brushes
When did you last wash your brushes? I don't remember the last time I washed mine..
I added a bit (too much) of makeup brush cleaning solution
The water is turning murky just from dipping the brush 🙂
This is actually incredibly fun and, most importantly, very fast!
There's still some foam residue, so I rinse it off and then spin it dry
It's actually very dry and fluffy after spinning ~
And it also comes with a spot to air dry and different attachments
I'm very happy with this purchase ! (And so is my skin! Haha )
I'm going to prepare yeast waffles for tomorrow's breakfast
Combine 190g flour, 4g yeast, 80g milk, 1 egg, 35g of sugar, and a bit of vanilla extract
Once the dough is formed, add in 30g of butter and combine
Cover and store in the fridge overnight
From 9 to 10 it's usually time for 🐢and I to catch up on our day
It's basically the only hour we have for the two of us haha
We enjoy some tea and toast to the fact that we did a great job today once again! 😆
I divided the dough into 6 parts to make 6 waffles
Yeast waffles are so cute and fluffy ✨
I'm going to top the waffles with some greek yoghurt
If you add some matcha powder into the yoghurt, you'll get a delicious matcha sauce !
Time to make it pretty ~
The weather calls for an iced latte ☺️
It feels like I'm at a cafe ☕️
Waffles go very well with coffee
I hope you enjoyed watching this video as much as I enjoyed making it